<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Dataware Logistics</title>
    <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/categories/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Dataware Logistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dawrlog.com/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BigQuery Data Types Examined &amp; Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/10/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, today I would like to talk about Bigquery, the datawarehouse managed service by Google Cloud. And I would like to explore its datatypes.
Google Cloud Platform has long been the cloud provider of choice for web analytics, with the impressive BigQuery being Google&amp;rsquo;s massively parallel processing (aka MPP) option. MPP databases are very common on Hadoop ecosystems.
BigQuery is very friendly to its users (let&amp;rsquo;s agree that BigQuery is as pleasant as its SQL knowledge), which fosters new users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Redshift Spectrum, Athena, and S3: Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/11/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, today I would like to present you how to explore your raw data stored by AWS S3 by using AWS managed analytical managed services. Today we will cover both AWS Redshift Spectrum and AWS Athena on our tutorial.
One of the significant challenges to data-driven companies comes when integrating different application systems.
Major public cloud providers, such as Amazon Web Services or Google Cloud Platform, offer robust products that are ready for your analytics needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
