<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dataware Logistics</title>
    <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dataware Logistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Redshift Query Queues: The Complete Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/9/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, hope everything is well.
Even the most potent database is still prone to the terrifying error any database system can face: query bottlenecks.
Sometimes the systems that manage our queries can&amp;rsquo;t process in the same way as we do. So our questions return accurate results as a result of extra processing power.
In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll present how Redshift query queues work. We&amp;rsquo;ll also cover how concurrency works at a high level on Redshift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental Loading: The Smarter Way to Update Data</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/8/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, hope everything is well.
A data warehouse aims to make sense of a specific subject over time by analyzing historical data. This system, also called the decision-making support system, can tackle trends as diverse as the percentage of client churn or beer consumption trends within a geographical area.
Incremental loading is one of those crucial issues you need to consider when defining your load pipelines.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what incremental loading is and why it&amp;rsquo;s so important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gRPC vs REST: Which Is Right for Your Application and Why?</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/13/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone, today we revisit the REST architecture, while comparing it to the gRPC calls.
A microservices framework sometimes looks like a dream, but it can be a nightmare when processing data. Transiting the data with less latency is not enough nowadays. It also needs to easily connect with systems. And not only does the speed matter, but it also needs to scale to fit your computing needs while not bleeding your infrastructure costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Argo Workflow ETL Examples.</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/5/</guid>
      <description>This post explores using Argo Workflows to orchestrate your data pipelines. To start, let&amp;rsquo;s refresh on what ETL is while designing our work&amp;rsquo;s high-level architecture. I&amp;rsquo;ll demonstrate how to set up your data pipelines to follow the structure more naturally. Then, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how to achieve the same result using directed acyclic graphs (DAGs). Last, I&amp;rsquo;ll summarize what we saw and present reasons to guide your choice of approach based on your project complexity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Argo Workflows Examples.</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/6/</guid>
      <description>We all know how Argo Workflows makes it easy to orchestrate parallel jobs on Kubernetes. While it’s most often associated with data processing and ETL projects, it’s useful for a lot more! These 10 workflows will change the way you see this Kubernetes orchestrator.
Let’s dive in!
Argo Workflows Setup
If you don&amp;rsquo;t currently have a workflow running, I suggest you create your first Argo Workflow to understand what we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways to Debug an Argo Workflow.</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/4/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone,
Today I would like to cover how to debug your Argo workflows, this comes handy when you need more details from your environment. Let’s check the two different approaches to debugging your Argo Workflow deployments.
First, we’ll use the Argo Command Line Interface, or CLI for short. Argo’s CLI commands cover many of the more common errors you see with workflows, such as misconfigurations. Then, we’ll see how to debug workflows using the Argo Workflows UI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archiving Argo Workflows: Postgres Database Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/2/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone, I hope you are doing well!
If you’re familiar with Argo Workflows, you already know that it can drive your CI/CD pipelines, manage your ETL processes, and orchestrate any set of tasks you can imagine for a Kubernetes cluster. But did you know that Argo knows how to archive the results of its workflows to a SQL database, too?
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how Argo Workflows archives workflow state into persistent storage using a Postgres database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Mitigate DDoS Attacks on Your APIs.</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/3/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating how a project&amp;rsquo;s delivery dates are sometimes so tight that you neglect the quality of your development application. Thanks to weak security policies, it&amp;rsquo;s even worse when your security team can&amp;rsquo;t catch the damage before it&amp;rsquo;s too late. To help you with that, I want to talk about targeted DDoS attacks and what they do to your application programming interface, also known as API endpoints. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what DDoS is and the problems it can cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BigQuery Data Types Examined &amp; Explained</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/10/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, today I would like to talk about Bigquery, the datawarehouse managed service by Google Cloud. And I would like to explore its datatypes.
Google Cloud Platform has long been the cloud provider of choice for web analytics, with the impressive BigQuery being Google&amp;rsquo;s massively parallel processing (aka MPP) option. MPP databases are very common on Hadoop ecosystems.
BigQuery is very friendly to its users (let&amp;rsquo;s agree that BigQuery is as pleasant as its SQL knowledge), which fosters new users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Value Stream DataOps?</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/12/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone, today we will check how to properly value stream your DataOps initiative.
Enhancements on data ingestion made evident the amount of data lost when generating insights. However, without guidance from methodologies like The DataOps Manifesto, some companies are still struggling to blend data pipelines from legacy databases, such as an ADABAS database, with new ones, such as MongoDB or Neo4j.
And it’s always good to point out that these legacy systems aren’t easy to let go of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is the Identity and Access Provisioning Lifecycle?</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/14/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone, today I want to revisit what is Identity and Access provisioning lifecycle phases.
With so much data being generated every second, it makes sense that data leakages are one of the biggest nightmares of any data-driven company. These days, we learn fast that weak security policies can be costly. This article will present one of the techniques to maintain your data secured: the identity and access provisioning lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Warehouse Design: The good, the bad, the ugly</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/1/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, hope everything is well.
One of the significant challenges in handling data comes from the massive amount of data your organization is most likely generating constantly. Having the ability to react quickly and accurately turns into a differential item among competitors.
More and more companies are becoming aware of the need to handle data wisely.
They&amp;rsquo;re looking for ways of getting the most out of their information. And this is probably where they first hear about data warehouses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Analyze PostgreSQL Data in Power BI.</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/7/</guid>
      <description>Hello all!
Today I want to discuss one of the dataviz tools that is getting more and more adoption; Power BI. Power BI increases its adoption among the most experienced users each day. Thanks to being a user-friendly tool with various data sources to connect to, it helps analyze distinct data sources within the same console.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to import your data stored on PostgreSQL with a desktop version of Power BI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Redshift Spectrum, Athena, and S3: Everything You Need to Know</title>
      <link>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dawrlog.com/posts/11/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone, today I would like to present you how to explore your raw data stored by AWS S3 by using AWS managed analytical managed services. Today we will cover both AWS Redshift Spectrum and AWS Athena on our tutorial.
One of the significant challenges to data-driven companies comes when integrating different application systems.
Major public cloud providers, such as Amazon Web Services or Google Cloud Platform, offer robust products that are ready for your analytics needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
